# **Ameer**Bajracharya

## **Full Stack Dev**



ameerbajracharya2022@gmail.com



+61 426 171 165



Unit 407, 1 Vermont Crescent, Riverwood, NSW 2210



https://www.ameer.com.np/

#### **Skills**

- Laravel
- Jquery
- Vue
- MySQL
- Bootstrap
- Javascript
- React
- GIT/Version Control

### **Profile**

I am a PHP - Laravel developer with 3+ years of experience in website design, development, and integration. advanced understanding of the Laravel framework and web development expertise in Jquery, and React.js. Previous experience in marketing and sales has helped me better understand customers, and product development, and give what they genuinely need in the realm of technology.

# **Work Experience**

#### **Backend Developer Freelancing**

#### Freelance | February 2020 to Present

- Build Client's website with PHP/MySQL/Javascript/Laravel framework/CSS/HTML.
- React.js, AJAX, and JSON were used to remove page refreshes.
- Freelancing CMS Development.
- Develop RESTful API for the required endpoints.
- Analyze the requirements and prototypes for the required projects.
- Building the team for the requirements and leading them to the final products.
- Finalizing the Prototype and Design for the Client.
- Design and Implement new features into the application for the clients.
- Database Analysis and Schema Design.
- Query optimization for better performance of the site.
- Analyzing Code for Clean Code Practice.
- www.harmopaathshala.com, www.studysar.com, https://grillsmichael.com/, https://www.ismiledentals.com/

# **Backend Developer**

#### Zillicom Real Estate | 15<sup>th</sup> March 2020 - 15<sup>th</sup> March 2022

- Refactoring and Optimization of the whole Codebase of the company.
- Development and maintenance of systems for cooperative use and also different websites for companies.
- Database Design and Schema Development.
- Data Flow Analysis.

#### **Awards**

Udemy Certifications
can be found on my
LinkedIn Profile.

#### Interest

- Data Analysis
- Business Analytics
- BPMN 2.0
- Stock Market

- RESTful API's for the mobile platform.
- CMS for Real Estate System was developed and deployed at www.zillicom.com and www.rental.zillicom.com.
- Self-Learning new skills to cooperate with the team.
- Collaborate with Product and Engineering team members to develop and design new product features.
- Continual Improvement to system architecture by refactoring old legacy codes.
- Working on instruction and leading the project in a direction with self-learned skills for a better outcome for the company.
- Used version controls Gitlab and Github.
- Worked on implementing Google Analytics and Code Debugging.
- Developed and Deployed features to facilitate related procedures and tools when necessary.
- Write clean, well-engineered code that conforms to accepted standards within the PHP community.
- Keeping track of website visits, and updating new content displays on the website.

## Referees

Madhav Shrestha Program Manager 3bees Education

<u>madhav@3beesgroup.com.au</u> +61 424 575 417

# **Laravel Developer**

Kite Nepal | 18th September 2019 - 25th Jan 2020

- Development and Deployment of E-Commerce Websites.
- Co-Operative Business Site Development.
- Learned JavaScript, Jquery, Basic React JS, and Vue JS.

#### **Education**

# **Master of Business Information System**

Australian Institute of Higher Education | 2022-2024

#### Majors:

- Database Management System
- Project Management
- System Analysis and Design
- Big Data and Visualisation
- Business Process Modeling
- Business Analytics
- Enterprise Systems
- Strategic Information Systems
- Sustainability and Enterprise 4.0
- Leading People in Digital Organisation.

Bachelor of Computer Science & Information Technology Swastik College of IT (Affiliated To Tribhuvan University) | 2016-2020

# Majors:

- Software Engineering
- Software Project Management
- Statistics I
- Statistics II
- Linear Algebra
- Calculus
- Data Structure and Algorithms
- Object Oriented Programming
- Database Management System
- Artificial Intelligence
- Data Warehousing and Data Mining